<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Danielle Gatland</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Danielle Gatland</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3D Modelling Forests to Create Synthetic Training Data for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/3d-modelling-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/3d-modelling-forest/</guid>
      <description>As part of a research and development project at Carbon Critical, I built a 3D modelled landscape in Blender for creating simulated renders of pine plantations. Initially, I simulated a single pine plantation from which we could render images from different positions and angles. I then extended this model using Blender&amp;rsquo;s Python integration to be able to simulate variations to:&#xA;The age of the pine plantation, including both the size of trees and &amp;ldquo;tree thinning&amp;rdquo; over time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Realistic Travel Time Catchments for Public Transport</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/gradient-isochrones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/gradient-isochrones/</guid>
      <description>In my public tranport planning work at MRCagney, I was often asked how we could better communicate the impacts of frequency and time of day on travel time catchments. A travel time catchment (an &amp;ldquo;isochrone&amp;rdquo;) is a map where an area is coloured to show what places are accessible within a travel time limit from a given origin.&#xA;Traditionally, a single isochrone map would be produced for a given journey start time, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Data Collection Apps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/data-collection-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/data-collection-apps/</guid>
      <description>In my work at MRCagney, we would occassionally undergo spatial data collection activities. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of our core work and would happen only a few times per year. We had never found the opportunity to invest the time to develop an app-based approach for data collection activities (and were instead still using pen and paper!). I used the opportunity of an upcoming project along with some free time to investigate the options for app-based spatial data collection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whangārei Housing Capacity and Feasibility Model</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/whangarei-housing-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/whangarei-housing-model/</guid>
      <description>I led the development of an online housing capacity model for Whangārei. The model computes the plan-enabled and commercially feasible housing capacity of the urban environment of Whangārei. It was developed to help the Council meet the statutory requirements of the National Policy Statement on Urban Development (2020). I was the project manager for this project and also led the data science for the data pre-processing elements of the project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Management Dashboard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project-management-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project-management-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>MRCagney Reports, an internal project management web app, began as a personal project of mine to improve on other project management platforms I had seen and/or trialled. After struggling to review timesheets and budgets while managing projects, and constantly applying manual techniques for each project I managed, I decided to try something new. I created an interactive dashboard to summarise timesheets and budgets for all projects in one place.&#xA;After developing an initial prototype, I shared my concept with my colleagues and management at MRCagney and got approval to develop it further.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NZ Arrivals (and the Impacts of COVID-19)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/nz-arrivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/nz-arrivals/</guid>
      <description>This was a personal interest project I created during one of Auckland&amp;rsquo;s COVID-19 lockdowns. As New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s borders went through various levels of restrictions on international travel to New Zealand, I was curious to see how the international arrivals fluctuated and compared to previous years. Rather than simply creating some charts at the time, I decided to create an interactive dashboard that I could update over time with new data, to monitor the trend of international arrivals as the world &amp;lsquo;returned to normal&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
