<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Visualisation on Danielle Gatland</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/data-visualisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Visualisation on Danielle Gatland</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/data-visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Realistic Travel Time Catchments for Public Transport</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/gradient-isochrones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/gradient-isochrones/</guid>
      <description>In my public tranport planning work at MRCagney, I was often asked how we could better communicate the impacts of frequency and time of day on travel time catchments. A travel time catchment (an &amp;ldquo;isochrone&amp;rdquo;) is a map where an area is coloured to show what places are accessible within a travel time limit from a given origin.&#xA;Traditionally, a single isochrone map would be produced for a given journey start time, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Management Dashboard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project-management-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project-management-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>MRCagney Reports, an internal project management web app, began as a personal project of mine to improve on other project management platforms I had seen and/or trialled. After struggling to review timesheets and budgets while managing projects, and constantly applying manual techniques for each project I managed, I decided to try something new. I created an interactive dashboard to summarise timesheets and budgets for all projects in one place.&#xA;After developing an initial prototype, I shared my concept with my colleagues and management at MRCagney and got approval to develop it further.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NZ Arrivals (and the Impacts of COVID-19)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/nz-arrivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/nz-arrivals/</guid>
      <description>This was a personal interest project I created during one of Auckland&amp;rsquo;s COVID-19 lockdowns. As New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s borders went through various levels of restrictions on international travel to New Zealand, I was curious to see how the international arrivals fluctuated and compared to previous years. Rather than simply creating some charts at the time, I decided to create an interactive dashboard that I could update over time with new data, to monitor the trend of international arrivals as the world &amp;lsquo;returned to normal&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
