<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geospatial on Danielle Gatland</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/geospatial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geospatial on Danielle Gatland</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/geospatial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Data Collection App with QGIS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/presentations/foss4g-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/presentations/foss4g-2023/</guid>
      <description>At the Free and Open Source Software for Geospatial (FOSS4G) Oceania 2023 conference, I gave a tutorial-style presentation on how to create a data collection app using QGIS and either one of the two leading data collections apps for QGIS: Mergin Maps or QField.&#xA;FOSS4G is about &amp;ldquo;free and open source software for geospatial&amp;rdquo; and the presentations at the FOSS4G conferences are often very inclusive and transparent with people sharing their experiences, code, and projects, and collaborating to help improve the skills of everyone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing Growth: An Online Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/presentations/nzpi-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/presentations/nzpi-2022/</guid>
      <description>At the New Zealand Planning Institute (NZPI) Conference 2023, I presented with my client, Hamish Sykes from Whangārei District Council, on the Whangārei Housing Capacity and Feasibility Model that we built for them.&#xA;We presented on:&#xA;The requirements of the National Policy Statement on Urban Development, for housing capacity and feasibility modelling The design requirements and scoping of our model to ensure it met both the national regulations and the district&amp;rsquo;s needs The multi-disciplinary collaboration required to develop the tool An overview and walkthrough of the tool in action and how the Council uses it </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whangārei Housing Capacity and Feasibility Model</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/presentations/whangarei-housing-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/presentations/whangarei-housing-webinar/</guid>
      <description>This webinar is about the Whangārei Housing Capacity and Feasibility Model project that I led while working at MRCagney.&#xA;In this webinar, Hamish Sykes (from Whangārei District Council) and I talk about:&#xA;What was required of the model Scoping and designing the online model framework An overview of what the model looks like and how it works How Council used the tool </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access to Public Transport</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/presentations/foss4g-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/presentations/foss4g-2019/</guid>
      <description>At the Free and Open Source Software for Geospatial (FOSS4G) Oceania 2019 conference, I presented on how we at MRCagney measured access to frequent public transport for key urban centres in New Zealand, for the New Zealand Transport Agency. This was a project we conducted annually for the New Zealand Transport Agency for several years to inform their annual reporting and metrics for the transport network performance across New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Realistic Travel Time Catchments for Public Transport</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/gradient-isochrones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/gradient-isochrones/</guid>
      <description>In my public tranport planning work at MRCagney, I was often asked how we could better communicate the impacts of frequency and time of day on travel time catchments. A travel time catchment (an &amp;ldquo;isochrone&amp;rdquo;) is a map where an area is coloured to show what places are accessible within a travel time limit from a given origin.&#xA;Traditionally, a single isochrone map would be produced for a given journey start time, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Data Collection Apps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/data-collection-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/data-collection-apps/</guid>
      <description>In my work at MRCagney, we would occassionally undergo spatial data collection activities. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of our core work and would happen only a few times per year. We had never found the opportunity to invest the time to develop an app-based approach for data collection activities (and were instead still using pen and paper!). I used the opportunity of an upcoming project along with some free time to investigate the options for app-based spatial data collection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whangārei Housing Capacity and Feasibility Model</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/whangarei-housing-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/whangarei-housing-model/</guid>
      <description>I led the development of an online housing capacity model for Whangārei. The model computes the plan-enabled and commercially feasible housing capacity of the urban environment of Whangārei. It was developed to help the Council meet the statutory requirements of the National Policy Statement on Urban Development (2020). I was the project manager for this project and also led the data science for the data pre-processing elements of the project.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
